<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts | Academic</title>
    <link>https://ishikasingh.github.io/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://ishikasingh.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Posts</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://ishikasingh.github.io/images/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>https://ishikasingh.github.io/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scientific Discovery and it’s Logic — A review</title>
      <link>https://ishikasingh.github.io/post/discovery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ishikasingh.github.io/post/discovery/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Find the article here on 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@ishikasingh95/scientific-discovery-and-its-logic-a-review-39b644e1a912?source=friends_link&amp;amp;sk=eba783255cc810bc1dbec6aaba3b0216&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social Limits on Freedom of Knowledge, based on ”The Dead Past” by Isaac Asimov</title>
      <link>https://ishikasingh.github.io/post/social_limits/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ishikasingh.github.io/post/social_limits/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At the end of the story, the four main characters are in agreement with regard to the dangerous impact of the chronoscope on society. Does this final agreement among these characters mean that all debates related to knowledge within the story are clearly resolved at the end of the story?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the debatable aspects about knowledge and its freedom, its relationship with and accountability to the society raised in the text as well as the opinions are dominantly as per the perspectives of its four main characters. So analyzing the question via all these roles will eventually either converge or diverge while establishing a final viewpoint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first debate, through the perspective of Dr. Potterley, was about scientific research being driven by power/restrictions (within an organization) versus that driven by intellectual curiosity. (The direct linking between power to restrictions is evident from - Research, he said, forced into a predesigned pattern by the powers that held the purse strings became slavish and had to stagnate). At first, he claims that the former setup will eventually stagnate, but he later corrects himself after realizing the possible social implications of uncontrolled research by adding that I still believe directed research can be useful. I’m not in favor of a retreat to total anarchy. But there must be a middle ground. Directed research can retain flexibility. He agrees to the notion that a third necessary angle to this debate is the societal impact for the reason that for scientists and researchers, science or any other kind of knowledge is separate from its application while for the society it’s largely purposive. For example for Foster (a researcher/knowledge producer) his contributions in the field of chronoscopy was largely the result of his curiosity towards the subject and concerns for science being suppressed and is less focused around its various applications. While for the society, represented by Potterley’s wife, science is largely seen as technology. Potterley puts society over intellectual curiously and takes a middle ground in the debate by employing social factors as the limit for freedom of science by realizing that People like my wife would outweigh us. Or maybe he’s making the impact of his argument bigger by generalizing, but is largely concerned about his wife, Caroline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moving on to Prof. Foster, his position in the debate was Why should direction and order benefit a factory and a ship but not scientific research?, which shifts to where Potterley earlier was, after he himself practices anarchism. Though there were subtle differences in Potterley’s earlier and Foster’s current position in terms of the ideals: For Potterley it’s that the knowledge building will eventually hit a wall, while for Foster the concern is for the possibility of existence of gaps or the unexplored ways of exploring science as he says It was just that scientific research had been directed from above and holes were left that could be filled in by anyone who looked in the right direction. And anyone might have if the government hadn’t actively tried to prevent it. Foster stood by his notions of ideal research (absolute freedom for practicing science) even after being exposed to the “dead past” argument by Potterley which indicates that he’s not much concerned about the society or the societal impacts of science. But later when he realizes the privacy invasion problems that would arise with his findings being publicized, he particularly points out to how Araman might have known about the safety-deposit box, after which he readily admits that he won’t publish without any other dialogue. This could implicate anything about Foster, he might be concerned only about his own privacy, or maybe he understands the bigger picture put forth by Araman. The later seems less plausible by the virtue of the preceding argument and also since throughout the text Foster was either concerned about science and its development or about his own curiosity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nimmo on other hand is largely materialistically and emotionally driven. This is evident when Nimmo says &amp;hellip;all the responsibility would be mine. His career would be saved. And if I were deprived of my science-writing license as a result, my exclusive possession of the chronometric data would set me up for life. Jonas would be angry, I expected that, but I could explain the motive and we would split the take fifty-fifty. He does not become the part of the debates related to knowledge, not significantly enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hence what we could clearly see is that none of the above characters, specially those closely involved in the debate, were dominantly driven by their concerns about the society, while they do understand the implications when they suffered themselves. The debate on knowledge being free seems to stand right until and unless it hits the one back who is trying to establish it. The debate doesn’t resolve around social causes but personal concerns for individual entities who are largely minding their own business and they don’t concern themselves with the wider view, while for the government figure (represented by Araman) it is indeed a social factor. The text once more critiques on the narrow division of work (previously by showing that it handicaps certain research possibilities), since it promotes minding one&amp;rsquo;s own business, it critiques on the lack of awareness and rationality of individuals which is a product of the way the organisation, described in the text, is. This inculcation of narrowed down thinking is evident for Foster throughout the text, for Potterley one specific evidence could be his dialogue: I had envisioned a chronoscope used for research purposes. All she (his wife) could see was the personal pleasure of returning neurotically to a personal past, a dead past. The pure researcher, Foster, is in the minority. The researchers are trained in the way that they couldn’t figure out the connections of their work in various other spheres, they are limited to certain dimensions. This leaves us with the question that whether the system is responsible for getting the debate resolved at such a primary level, i.e., around personal concerns, for all the individuals making up the system. Is it also responsible for their ignorance of such adverse implications of their work? And would it have been a better scenario, as in what happened in the end wouldn’t have happened, if the system would have been such that the individuals (Potterley and Foster) could have realized the implications earlier than when they were made to by a rulekeeper (Araman). The debate raises questions on the credibility of the system. Would it have been a better scenario if the organisation would have been such that knowledge would have been unrestricted so that a scientist/historian/researcher could also think about the social impacts and could remain armed about their work without falling into the debate on freedom of knowledge? Thus the text, by becoming a critique of the present organization, presents a possibility of inexistence of the debate on knowledge being free or restricted by unrestricting it, and giving individuals the freedom to look across and the responsibility of being wholly aware of the implications of their work. And hence, the text presents a resolved scenario for the debate by critiquing the present unresolved scenario.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Work Culture Differences and its Relation with Nation’s Growth: India and Japan</title>
      <link>https://ishikasingh.github.io/post/workculture/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ishikasingh.github.io/post/workculture/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Work culture of a place encloses its history and the beliefs which are developed over time. Further, it also relates with the way the society interacts, preferred personalities of individual and society, social orders and hierarchies, etc. While we can claim about the reliability of the above correlations, there are no concrete dependencies found between the work culture and the nation’s growth. One can derive some conclusions on the basis of available examples though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Japanese business associates are generally known for being quick decision makers. They are strict about their schedules and deadlines. They tend to follow a collective decision-making process where they involve every individual who is remotely associated with the outcomes, irrespective of the hierarchy. The work place is treated more as a society where individuals form relations within the constraints of work distribution. The environment is more open for discussion and easy reaching out for consultation to higher authorities to ensure faster accomplishment of work. Japanese people are also known to have faith in work and in building trust via building respect, as I came to know while reading articles from people who had experienced working in Japanese firms. This kind of culture is termed as small-power-distance situation, by Geert Hofstede(a known Dutch psychologist) as one of the culture dimensions defining a nation’s culture, where subordinates and superiors consider each other as existentially equal; the hierarchical system is just an inequality of roles, established for convenience. Organizations are fairly decentralized, with limited numbers of supervisory personnel. Salary ranges between top and bottom jobs are relatively small; workers are highly qualified, and high-skill manual work has a higher status than low skilled office work. Privileges for higher-ups are basically undesirable. This collective procedure of decision-making serves an advantage of improving quality which takes into account, more or less, the needs of all kinds of communities and facilitates collective growth, which is an important factor to be considered. This ensures that the nation’s various economic averages really depict the situation and should not hide wide disparities within it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Japan saw a tremendous transformation during Meiji Restoration(1867-1912). The period saw rapid industrialization in Japan, with urbanization (and its problems) to match. Both the long-suppressed merchant class and noble and ex-samurai families tried their hands at commerce and building industrial empires. The reforms were promoted with the following slogans: ‘Fukoku kyōhei’ (rich country, strong military), ‘Shokusan kōgyō’ (increase production, promote industry), Bunmei kaika (civilization and enlightenment), and ‘Wakon yōsai’ (Japanese spirit, Western learning). Japan also grew greatly in the sector of film making (anime and comic).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Japan’s main focus during its recovery from wars and dominance of other empires was to build the nation as a whole and establish a collective work culture, India was struggling hard to settle peacefully with its wide diversity and is still struggling with it. Evidences from Indian history suggests the profoundness of Varna/Caste system. The roles and responsibilities were assigned as per the social ranks or the castes - Brahmin, Kshatriya, Vaishya and Shudra. The decision-making power had a tall hierarchy, which is still prevalent in the country at some places to considerable extents. The classification of work was clearly laid down in old manuscripts, ancient sculptures of Manusmriti, and one of the all time popular book Economics and Politics - Arthashashtra where Kautilya examined the roles of a King. So is the work culture in India today. Most of the firms have established tall hierarchies with distribution of roles and positions from most important to least important. Moreover, Indians tend to allocate the decision-making power in a few hands, the history and culture provide proofs for the fact that power was centralized to elder male members of the family, without involvement of the younger or less experienced or female members. These practices are also taken to the prevalent work culture, where decision-making is mostly in the hands of a few higher rank officials. The inclusion of other lower ranked officials is not considered important. Many times there is discrimination on the basis of caste, class and gender as well. This situation is defined as large-power-distance situation by Hofstede where superiors and subordinates consider each other as existentially unequal; the hierarchical system is based on this existential inequality. Subordinates expect to be told what to do. Subordinates remain dependent upon supervisors. Salary systems show wide gaps. Workers are relatively uneducated, and manual work has much lower status than office work. Moreover, superiors are entitled to various privileges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the current situation, India tends to follow Individualism more than Collectivism. People care more about themselves and their immediate family members. While Japan has achieved a group-fulfilling development structure and tend to protect each other in exchange for unquestioned loyalty. As per the surveys as well as individual feedback, the work culture in Japan is taken more as a family than an office. People remain more involved along with being efficient, and they do not separate their families from office folks, while in India the workplace and the home are the two different entities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to studies done on Japanese management style and its relation with its tremendous growth there exist some reliable correlations. Robert H. Hayes(1981) suggests that Japanese success formula was their best manufacturing and management practices and policies such as clean facilities, responsible employees, little or no inventories by ensuring the absence of work stoppages, almost no rejected products, and the &amp;ldquo;just-in-time&amp;rdquo; and good risk management system. Japanese, unlike Americans, gave comparatively greater priority to quality over deadlines, both the factors were extremely important to them though. Employees in Japan are more eager to contribute and managers are more adaptable to new management practices which resulted in improved productivity through higher levels of motivation, greater sharing of decision-making, stronger employee commitment, and increased job satisfaction. Ouchi(1981) says that once the collective decision is taken, it becomes the sole responsibility of the group to accomplish it. Three pillar of Japanese industrial relations system are lifetime employment, the seniority wage and promotion system, and enterprise based unions. Such practices promote their culture as well as faith in work. Or in other words, the Japanese culture teaches the idea of faith in work and social benefits. The fuel behind their strong organizational structure is the trust they develop in relationships. A 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.japantimes.co.jp/news/2017/12/12/national/japanese-workers-feel-guilty-taking-time-off-use-fewer-holidays-international-peers-survey/#.WrG3Y5PwbMI&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;survey by Expedia&lt;/a&gt; found that Japanese workers only take around half of their vacation days, and many workers reported feeling guilty whenever they took time off. These results again establish their faith and willingness towards work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indian business and management system is featured by individualistic growth,   power distribution, optimistic towards new opportunities, open towards research and entrepreneurship, the nation lacks at many fronts though. Domination of family, highly bureaucratic government systems, labor laws and human resource practices are some areas where managerial gaps needs to be addressed. Nevertheless, the changes coming along with the rise of sectors like software, services, automobile, pharmaceuticals and biotechnology have proved the nation&amp;rsquo;s capability to fight at international standards set by developed countries. India, being a land of contradictions, becomes a place for all sorts of diversities and conflicts. The workplaces accommodating these diversities in a confined zone gives rise to hierarchies in several dimensions, namely position, caste, religion, etc. along with their existing minority and majority. Along with the huge financial gaps and the unavoidable problems of corruption ranging from punctuality towards work to the matters of trust on an unknown individual sitting at a government desk, becomes a part of the big challenge standing against the nation towards its growth. People remain more focused on individual benefits, rather than community benefits. The work culture itself promotes such lusts by providing extra benefits to higher rank officials. This structure, arising from the financial gaps, in turn, contributes to widening of this gap. Thus, the economic averages shown doesn’t depict the true picture, representation of very poor gets neutralized when added with stats of very rich. India has several internal fights to overcome before competing with those standing outside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, India’s global image in economic success has boosted recently. In recent years, India’s GDP grew with the rate of 8 percent average. Demographically 70 percent of India’s population is less than 35 years of age. Instead of huge population of 1.1 billion, effect of growth can be seen everywhere in India (Since 2005). Indian product quality is reaching world standards. It emerged as leading supplier of IT and IT enabled services. It produces the largest pool of Doctors, Engineers, and MBA&amp;rsquo;s per year. India’s competitive advantage lies, firstly, in large pool of English-speaking knowledge intensive human resource and second, India offers very attractive cost structure (Chatterjee &amp;amp; Nankervis, 2007). Recently India emerged as favorable destination for business in world. There’s a lot of scope of development in human resource though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the conclusion statement, culture-wise Japan manages to stand out by making their work their faith, and their office their family. Such a culture proves to be productive and beneficial for the nation in terms of growth and development. While India’s culture is more focused towards promoting their community, be it religion-wise, caste-wise, class-wise, or gender-wise, lacks faith and motivation towards work. A predominant chauvinistic behavior leads to cultivation of corruption and ill-direction, thus treating work as a duty which is important for money and survival instead taking it as duty which is necessary for nation’s growth. These arguments, thus, can be included while talking about why India lags from Japan.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can an AI Acquire Human Personality?</title>
      <link>https://ishikasingh.github.io/post/ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ishikasingh.github.io/post/ai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Find the article here on 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@ishikasingh95/can-an-ai-acquire-human-personality-9c9b0d774b5f?source=friends_link&amp;amp;sk=45d942558da55baa04cefd21c50ca277&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;.
I wrote this long time back, but published later on medium.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
